# Bárbara Diana

Porto • +351 910 288 357 • bdianapinto@outlook.com

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I'm a software engineer with a multidisciplinary background in data engineering, software testing, and quality systems. I bring over 4 years of hands-on experience developing data pipelines, optimizing quality processes, and building reliable systems across Agile and safety-critical environments. With dual degrees in Business Management and Informatics Engineering, I bridge technical insight and strategic thinking.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Critical Software S.A.

2023 - Present

#### **Software Tester**

- Designed, implemented and executed manual and automated integration testing for safety-critical systems, ensuring compliance with CENELEC standards.
- Contributed to the review process of system requirements with a crossfunctional team, identifying faults and inconsistencies, as well as testability.

DataCentric 2023 - 2023

# **Data Engineer**

- Provided support on several Agile projects, related to transforming raw datasets into analytical tables for decision-making purposes.
- Developed an internship project, focused on real-time data analytics applied to a dynamic recommendation algorithm.

## NIBBLE - Engenharia Lda.

2019 - 2022

# Quality Manager & Management Assistant

- Implemented and managed an ISO 9001 QMS and NP 4457 R&D integrated system.
- Built internal tools (dashboards, document automation, surveys) to enhance operational efficiency.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering**

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto 2019 - 2023

## **Erasmus + | European Project Semester**

St. Pölten University of Applied Sciences 2022 - 2023

## Bachelor's Degree in Business Management

Faculdade de Economia da Universidade do Porto 2016 - 2019

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Testing & QA Tools**

- JUnit
- Mockito
- Jira

#### **Big Data Tools**

- · Spark
- · PySpark
- Kafka
- Docker
- SQL
- Azure

#### **Automation & CI/CD**

- Jenkins
- Git

#### **Programming Languages**

- C
- C#
- C++
- Java
- Python

### Soft Skills

- · Attention to detail
- · Organization
- Proactivity
- Problem-solving
- · Team player

# Languages

- · Portuguese
- English

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

ISTQB® Foundation Level (CTFL) -Syllabus 2018

2024 PSTQB